suppose the golden ratio were a rational
number that means we could write it as A
over B where A and B are positive
integers and this is in lowest terms the
existence of two such integers means
that we can draw this regular pentagon
with a diagonal of length a and a side
length of B the pictured green triangle
is known as a Golden Triangle when we
swing this side length down into the
Golden Triangle we create a second
triangle pictured in red that's also a
Golden Triangle with corresponding side
lengths B and A minus B but because
these two triangles are similar that
means that A over B is equal to B / a
minus B this means that the golden ratio
Fe is equal to B over a minus B but
that's a contradiction since B is less
than a and a minus B is less than b so
FAL A over B couldn't have been in
lowest terms this proof means that the
golden ratio fee must be irrational